MARIBETH PALBAN

Mobile: +65 9753 7908 (Whats App) Alt Mobile: +31 687 709 342 (Whats App)

Email: maribethpalban@gmail.com

Skype: Maribeth.Palban

SUMMARY

Results-driven and client-focused professional with 16+ years' record assessing, defining, and delivering data management, business development, and pre-sales solutions for global leaders across industries

Multiple Engagements with location across Europe, Asia, Australia, and North America. Various roles in SAP CRM Business Consulting, Project Management, and Business

AREAS EXPERTISE

- Readily interface between business users at all levels to communicate technical solutions.
- Engaging presenter, clearly articulate results to inform data-driven decisions.
- Skilled in negotiation and persuasion.
- Thorough in assessing and defining scalability, maintainability, costs, and risks of proposals.
- Possess expertise managing complex projects according to Agile methodology.
- Demonstrated success leading technical and cross functional teams of up to fifteen people.
- Hands-on knowledge of SAP business processes for manufacturing, medical, banking, utilities, and other industries.
- Competently guide complex system integrations, customizations, and upgrades.
- Recognized talent for facilitating collaboration among diverse teams to devise winning solutions.
- Proactive problem solver, accomplished researcher and analyst.
- History of designing processes that translate analysis into business solutions.
- Possess depth of technical knowledge applicable to broad range of SAP systems, structures, and interfaces.
- Adept at planning, directing, and documenting all test phases including user acceptance testing
- Steadfast in confidence and versatility in ambiguous and rapidly changing landscapes.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERTISE

Guide, analyse, test, and provide subject matter expertise for a broad range of technical projects serving clients in the insurance, healthcare, IT, ecommerce, automotive, and shipping industries.

Gather requirements from prospective and existing clients. Collaborate across functions to devise proof-of-concept demonstrations for process improvements, system upgrades

SKILLS

Programming Skills

Technical SAP R/3 ABAP / RICEF (Reports, Interfaces,

> Conversions, Batch Data Conversion, LSMW, User

Exits, Formulas & Requirements, SAPscript,

SMARTFORMS), OOP,

Python, SQL

CRM Platforms SAP, Sugar CRM,

Salesforce, MS Dynamics, Oracle

eCommerce & Marketing

SAP Hybris

SAP Modules SAP CRM Leasing,

Service, Sales, Marketing, UBB Contracts, Interaction Center, Billing, SD, MM,

FICO, SRM

Data Management

SAP HANA, Data Services, Business Information Warehouse (BW), Data Services,

Tableau

Fiori UX/UI

Methodologies

Agile/SCRUM

Testing / Analysis Tools &

HP QC, Jira

SAP Modules

Scripts

SAP CRM Financial

Service Leasing, UBB Contracts, CRM Services, Sales, Marketing & E-

Commerce, SAP R/3 ECC SD, MM, FICO,

FICA

and integrations, and other change initiatives. Create storylines and scripts that demonstrate capabilities of proposed solutions to internal and external stakeholders. Deliver engaging and dynamic demonstrations that consistently lead to contracts.

Plan and strategize projects according to Agile methodology. Conduct Scrum sessions with cross-functional teams to clarify requirements, propose solutions, and identify lean strategies.

Analyse legacy and proposed system processes. Guide analysis and testing throughout and following integration and implementation of new systems. Ensure systems are configured according to client needs. Train users at all skill levels

PROJECT EXPERIENCES

SAP CRM Leasing Functional Consultant, (April 2018 – *Present*)

Westhouse Consulting, Gmbh and SAP Netherlands

Project: Philips Blue Heart Systems implementation of full SAP CRM Leasing tool for patient monitoring technologies and emerging technologies such as Data Analytics, Robotics Process Automation, Artificial Intelligence. It is an integrated solution with other platforms such as SFDC, Servicenow, SRM, SAP ERP SD

Business Analyst, Pricing & Customer Support, (Jan 2018 – March 2018)

Neptune Orient Lines, Singapore

Project: Migration of pricing data from legacy (Mainframe & Oracle) system to SAP platform SAP TM module

Project Manager / Business Analyst, (May 2017 – July 2017)

Sky Premium Pte Ltd., Singapore

Project: Salesforce implementation and integration with mobile and eCommerce website

Senior Business Consultant, (Dec 2015 – Nov 2016)

Convista Consulting Pte Ltd., Singapore

Project: SAP CRM implementations for Marketing, Sales and Promotions campaigns and integration of e-commerce & marketing solution for banking, insurance and utilities industries

SAP CRM Business Process and Solution Design Lead, (Dec 2013 - April 2015)

Seaco Global Pte Ltd., UK & Singapore

Project: IT Transformation by relocating Internal IT support services from London to Singapore, Infrastructure upgrade to AWS Cloud to reduce IT operating costs and performance tuning for billing and postings

Projects under Ecenta Asia Pacific Pte Ltd (Nov 2006 - June 2013)

SAP CRM Pre-Sales & Business Development Consultant and Pricing Consultant

Projects in SAP CRM Full Service Leasing Implementation for Leaseplan (Australia), Fiat/FGA Capita (Italy), Fiat/FGA Capital (Austria), Volvo Trucks (Sweden), and Crown Forklift Trucks (USA)

SAP CRM Service Functional Consultant, (Jan 2011 - Feb 2011)

Intel Corporation (USA)

Project: Enterprise Information Management, a service request tool for innovative products still to be developed

SAP CRM Service Functional Consultant & Design Lead, (Dec 2010 - March 2011)

Carl Zeiss Gmbh

Project: Field service mobility solution to be integrated to SAP CRM Service

SAP CRM Service Functional Consultant & Design Lead, (May 2007 – Nov 2010)

Leaseplan (Australia)

Project: Full SAP CRM Full Service Leasing solution with Vehicle Service Management with External portal for vehicle service maintenance

SAP CRM Consultant, (Feb 2007 – Oct 2007)

Multimedia Development Corporation, Malaysia

Project: Full SAP CRM Lead and Activity Management

SAP CRM Consultant, (Nov 2006 – Dec 2006)

Lenovo (Beijing, China)

Project: Full SAP CRM Account Management, Opportunity and Sales Contracts

Projects under HTL Manufacturing Pte Ltd & Origem Solutions Pte Ltd (Oct 2003 - Aug 2006)

HTL Manufacturing Pte Ltd (Singapore)

SAP ERP SD Techno-Functional Consultant

Project: Full cycle implementation with Deloitte Consulting for SAP ERP solutions with focus on SD and MM technofunctional roles

Singapore

Projects under Accenture Inc. Manila (Oct 2000 - Aug 2003)

SAP ABAP Technical Developer

Dupont (Feb 2002 – Aug 2003)

Project: US SAP R/3 4.6C implementation for FI and SD modules, Involved in Technical Design and development of Sales and Distribution forms using SMARTFORMS.

Glatfelter (May 2002 – July 2002)

Project: Full cycle implementation SAP R/3 4.6C implementation for FI and SD modules

Consol Energy (February 2002 – May 2002)

Project: North American implementation of SAP version 4.6C. The scope of the project (called Capability Release 1) is a full conversion of SAP's FICO module for all Consol locations and implementation of MM and PM modules for Consol's Enlow Fork Coal mine. Involved in ABAP development for MM reports.

Dupont Dow Elastomers (May 2000 – Feb 2002)

Project: Involved in development and support for its ABAP RICEF (Reports, Interface, Conversions, Enhancements and Forms) Design, Build and Run phases for Logistics modules.

QUALIFICATIONS & EDUCATION

Certifications & Training:

•	2016:	SAP Hybris eCommerce – SAP India,	•	2001:	Chemical Industry Foundation
		Bangalore	•	2000:	PDP Central Arthur Andersen LC
•	2014:	ITIL Foundation in IT Service Management	•	2000:	Database Fundamentals
		(License 5110480.20299869)	•	2000:	SAP R/3 3.0: ABAP/4 Fundamentals
•	2013:	Project Management Professional	•	2000:	SAP R/3 2.2: Intro to Financial Accounting
•	2009:	IUT240 Contract Accounts & Receivable	•	2000:	SAP R/3 2.2: Intro to Materials Management
•	2002:	TABW20 SAP BW Presentation	•	2000:	SAP R/3 2.2: Intro to Sales & Distribution
•	2001:	SAP ABAP Training & DET	•	2000:	SAP R/3 3.0: Advanced System Operations
•	2001:	Manila SC's Process Orientation	•	2000:	SAP R/3 3.0: Basic System Operations
	2001:	Manila SC Capability Maturity Model		2000:	SAP R/3 2.2: Technical Systems Overview

Education:

1996-2000: BSc (cum laude) in Accountancy, Cum Laude

Ateneo de Davao University (Davao City, Philippines)

PREVIOUS EMPLOYERS

> Accenture Inc. Manila, Philippines

Team Lead (Sept 2003 - Oct 2003)

Senior Software Engineer (Sept 2002 - Sept 2003)

Analyst (Oct 2000 - Aug 2002)

Reason for Leaving: Better career opportunities overseas

Origem Solutions Pte Ltd

SAP Techno-Functional Consultant (Oct 2003 - Sept 2005)

Reason for Leaving: Conversion to permanent staff

HTL Manufacturing Pte Ltd

SAP System Specialist (Oct 2005 – Oct 2006)

Reason for Leaving: Better career opportunities in Consulting after finishing the full life cycle and roll out projects.

Ecenta Asia Pacific Pte Ltd

Senior CRM Consultant (Nov 2006 – June 2013)

Reason for Leaving: There was a need to take a break due to the stressful project and coordinating teams from different time zone

Seaco Global Pte Ltd SEP

SAP CRM Business Process Analyst/ SAP Solution Lead (Dec 2013 – April 2015)

Reason for Leaving: Restructuring due to Merger and Acquisition by HNA, besides the initial work of building up a new IT support team and IT infrastructure and application improvements has been completed

Convista Consulting Pte Ltd ...

Senior Business Process Consultant (Dec 2015 - Nov 2016)

Reason for Leaving: Relocation and bundling of all resources due to cost cutting reasons

➢ Sky Premium Pte Ltd SEP

Project Manager / Business Analyst (Dec 2015 – July 2017)

Reason for Leaving: Contract has ended

American President Lines / Neptune Orient Lines

Business Analyst Pricing Expert (Jan 2018 – March 2018)

Reason for Leaving: Acquisition and Migration to parent system in which they have their own IT support

Westhouse Consulting GmbH (26.02.2018 – Present)

SAP CRM Leasing Functional Consultant

End Client: SAP NL / Philips Electronics Nederland B.V.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Availability: Immediate

LinkedIn: <u>LinkedIn_Maribeth_Palban</u>

Nationality: Filipino, Singapore PR

Education: Bachelor of Science in Accountancy

Languages: English, Filipino, Italian

Contact Email: <u>maribethpalban@gmail.com</u>

Alternative Contact Email: maribethpalban@lycos.com / palban.maribeth@yahoo.com

➤ Mobile: +65 9753 7908 (Whats App) / +31 687 709 342 (Whats App)

> Skype: Maribeth.Palban

References available on request